"lang"
{
	"Language" "schinese"
	"Tokens"
	{
		"Prelude.ding_on"						"<sfx>[扬声器音调]"
		"Prelude.announce_chime"				"<sfx>[扬声器音调]"
		
		"Prelude.box_destroyed_mike-1"			"<clr:75,175,255>哦，小心点！你毁坏了那个方块！"
		"Prelude.box_destroyed_mike-2"			"<clr:75,175,255>好，我会通过分配器给您再发送一个"
		"Prelude.box_destroyed_mike-3"			"<clr:75,175,255>这次小心点..."
		
		"Prelude.box_destroyed_erik-1"			"<clr:255,200,100>噢上帝！你对那个方块做了啥？"
		"Prelude.box_destroyed_erik-2"			"<clr:255,200,100>一个就价值500美元啊！请小心点"
		"Prelude.box_destroyed_erik-3"			"<clr:255,200,100>正在给你发送另外一个"
		
		"Prelude.box_destroyed_peter-1"			"<clr:75,255,175>说真的，别再搞坏那些破方块了"
		"Prelude.box_destroyed_peter-2"			"<clr:75,255,175>每次我都得登录这个蹩脚的终端，然后输入一大堆复杂命令"
		"Prelude.box_destroyed_peter-3"			"<clr:75,255,175>比如说 /etc/init.d/boxdropper reload"
		
		"Prelude.toilet_thank"					"<I>伙伴型厕所虽然不能说话，但是能帮你处理翔"
		
		"Prelude.level_01_welcome-1"			"<I>欢迎来到光圈科技电脑辅助丰富学习中心"
		"Prelude.level_01_welcome-2"			"<I>我希望您在短暂的停留期间过的愉快"
		"Prelude.level_01_welcome-3"			"<I>您的样本已经处理完毕 我们现已准备好开始试验"
		"Prelude.level_01_welcome-4"			"<sfx><clr:255,200,100>[笑声]"
		"Prelude.level_01_welcome-4b"			"<clr:75,175,255>咋了？"
		"Prelude.level_01_welcome-5"			"<clr:255,200,100>别逗了，你在说什么啊 Mike？别废话了"
		"Prelude.level_01_welcome-6"			"<clr:75,175,255>嘿，这是例行手续。我们必须在每一次样本开始试验时朗读这些内容"
		"Prelude.level_01_welcome-7"			"<clr:255,200,100>哦，看在上帝份上，不要称她为'样本'，她有名字，Mike..."
		"Prelude.level_01_welcome-8"			"<clr:75,175,255>好吧，那么... 你好 Abby，今天过的怎样？我是 Mike，我将观察你通过这个测试"
		"Prelude.level_01_welcome-9"			"<clr:255,200,100>很好，这样好多了！别担心 Abby，我们知道这个测试看起来很奇怪，但我们会关注你的"
		"Prelude.level_01_welcome-10"			"<clr:255,200,100>并且我们也可以帮助你，但要保密！我们这里不允许这样做"
		"Prelude.level_01_welcome-13"			"<clr:255,200,100>哈，我想我们该开始测试了"
		"Prelude.level_01_welcome-14"			"<clr:75,175,255>哦对。开始吧 Abby！走出这个房间"
		
		"Prelude.level_01_test_00_success-1"	"<clr:255,200,100>好，你做的非常好。随便在房间里转转吧，没什么危险的"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_00_success-2"	"<clr:75,175,255>理论上没有，但请留意，有些门会在你通过时自动开启"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_00_success-3"	"<clr:255,200,100>我想他的意思是，'别傻站在这，门要自己开'"
		
		"Prelude.level_01_test_01_entry-1"		"<clr:75,175,255>又见面了 Abby。我是 Mike"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_01_entry-2"		"<clr:255,200,100>兄弟，她知道你是谁。我们两分钟前刚讲过话"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_01_entry-3"		"<clr:75,175,255>我知道，但这是规定，在每个实验室开始时自我介绍"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_01_entry-4"		"<clr:255,200,100>好吧 - 欢迎来到第一个实验室"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_01_entry-5"		"<clr:255,200,100>您的目标位于房间中央"
		
		"Prelude.level_01_test_01_portalgun-1"	"<clr:75,175,255>这是光圈科技手持传送设备"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_01_portalgun-2"	"<clr:255,200,100>又称传送枪，随你便"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_01_portalgun-3"	"<clr:75,175,255>确实，但它不是武器。实际上，连枪也算不上"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_01_portalgun-4"	"<clr:255,200,100>它可以创造跨纬度传送门... 之类的事情"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_01_portalgun-5"	"<clr:75,175,255>请注意，这个版本并未完全升级。你只能用它创建橘色传送门"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_01_portalgun-6"	"<clr:255,200,100>小心使用，好吗。如果你犯蠢把自己搞死了，我们可不负责"
		
		"Prelude.level_01_test_01_success-1"	"<clr:255,200,100>嘿 Mike？这些橙色和蓝色的传送门有什么区别？"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_01_success-2"	"<clr:75,175,255>问得好！"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_01_success-3"	"<clr:75,175,255>一个是蓝色，另一个是橘色，除此之外，没了"
		
		"Prelude.level_01_test_02_entry-1"		"<clr:75,175,255>欢迎来到第2实验室"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_02_entry-2"		"<clr:255,200,100>咖啡时间到！我们要休息下。你该做啥做啥"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_02_entry-3"		"<clr:75,175,255>并且独立完成"
		
		"Prelude.level_01_test_02_success-1"	"<clr:75,175,255>干的不错！"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_02_success-2"	"<clr:75,175,255>前往下个房间"
		
		"Prelude.level_01_test_03_entry-1"		"<clr:255,200,100>欢迎来到第3试验室"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_03_entry-2"		"<clr:255,200,100>现在你知道如何使用传送枪了，在这个房间，我们将给你一个全新版本"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_03_entry-3"		"<clr:255,200,100>别错过了"
		
		"Prelude.level_01_test_03_portalgun-1"	"<clr:75,175,255>好的，你的传送枪现在全副武装"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_03_portalgun-2"	"<clr:75,175,255>你可以同时创建一个蓝色和橘色的传送门"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_03_portalgun-3"	"<clr:255,200,100>我们不打算向你解释它的工作原理，请你自己试试"
		
		"Prelude.level_01_test_03_nag-1"		"<clr:255,200,100>你这样做是不行的"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_03_nag-2"		"<clr:75,175,255>记住你学过的关于动量守恒的知识"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_03_nag-3"		"<clr:75,175,255>进得快，出得快，飞得远"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_03_nag-4"		"<clr:75,175,255>就这一次，我们将通过稍微调整平台来帮助您，但这是唯一一次！"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_03_nag-5"		"<clr:255,200,100>这个小技巧以后会救你一命的，留意下"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_03_nag-6"		"<clr:255,200,100>还有，不要告诉任何人我们帮助过，会造成不好的后果"
		
		"Prelude.level_01_test_03_success-1"	"<clr:75,175,255>干的好，我就知道你能行"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_03_success-2"	"<clr:255,200,100>希望你不介意我的小小玩笑"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_03_success-3"	"<clr:75,175,255>你在说什么..？"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_03_success-4"	"<clr:255,200,100>我指实验室里被我移动的墙壁"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_03_success-5"	"<clr:255,200,100>移了也是没用！"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_03_success-6"	"<clr:75,175,255>不好笑，Erik。这是很严肃的事情"
		"Prelude.level_01_test_03_success-7"	"<clr:255,200,100>噢，拜托..."
		
		"Prelude.level_02_test_04_trap-1"		"<sfx><clr:255,200,100>[笑声]"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_04_trap-2"		"<clr:75,175,255>嘿，小心！"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_04_trap-3"		"<clr:255,200,100>拜托！别是这么愚蠢的死法！"
		
		"Prelude.level_02_test_04_entry-1"		"<clr:75,175,255>欢迎来到第4实验室"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_04_entry-2"		"<clr:75,175,255>我是 Mike，再一次"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_04_entry-3"		"<clr:255,200,100>我是 Erik，但快不是了"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_04_entry-4"		"<clr:75,175,255>噢，为啥？你要离开？"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_04_entry-5"		"<clr:255,200,100>是的，去一会。去哪你无须知道"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_04_entry-6"		"<clr:75,175,255>噢，好吧"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_04_entry-7"		"<clr:75,175,255>我还以为你要--"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_04_entry-8"		"<clr:255,200,100>够了！我去去就来"
		
		"Prelude.level_02_test_04_nag-1"		"<clr:75,175,255>嘿，请不要损坏实验室设施"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_04_nag-2"		"<clr:75,175,255>这些东西很值钱的，我可不想承担赔偿责任"
		
		"Prelude.level_02_test_05_entry-1"		"<clr:75,175,255>嘿，你已经在第5实验室了？我看不到你！"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_05_entry-2"		"<clr:75,175,255>噢，你是在那里。我想我错过了上个实验室的未尾"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_05_entry-3"		"<clr:75,175,255>我不得不更关注些其他状况"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_05_entry-4"		"<clr:75,175,255>不管怎么说，祝你好运"
		
		"Prelude.level_02_test_05_success-1"	"<clr:75,175,255>你的进步神速！"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_05_success-2"	"<clr:75,175,255>小心，因为下个房间是... 呃... 棘手"
		
		"Prelude.level_02_test_06_entry-1"		"<clr:75,175,255>墙体启动。祝你好运"
		
		"Prelude.level_02_test_06_fail-1"		"<clr:75,175,255>太糟糕了，你失败了"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_06_fail-2"		"<clr:75,175,255>你知道光圈科技的规矩，是吧？"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_06_fail-3"		"<clr:75,175,255>没有第二次机会"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_06_fail-4"		"<clr:75,175,255>我很抱歉 - 测试结束"
		
		"Prelude.level_02_test_06_success-1"	"<clr:75,175,255>恭喜你！好险啊..."
		"Prelude.level_02_test_06_success-2"	"<clr:255,200,100>嘿，我回来了！我错过了什么好戏么？"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_06_success-3"	"<clr:75,175,255>呃，实际上，你..."
		"Prelude.level_02_test_06_success-4"	"<clr:255,200,100>噢 不！那是我最最喜欢的一个实验室！"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_06_success-5"	"<clr:255,200,100>她太快了。她还活着？"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_06_success-6"	"<clr:75,175,255>当然了！"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_06_success-7"	"<clr:255,200,100>咳。真糟糕"
		
		"Prelude.level_02_test_07_nag-1"		"<clr:255,200,100>嗨 Abby！你知道40％的测试对象在前面一个实验室挂掉了么？"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_07_nag-2"		"<clr:255,200,100>我确信这能让你高兴些"
		
		"Prelude.level_02_test_07_entry-1"		"<clr:75,175,255>欢迎来到第7实验室"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_07_entry-2"		"<clr:255,200,100>如果我是你，我会特别小心这些墙"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_07_entry-3"		"<clr:75,175,255>这一次，我建议你听他的劝"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_07_entry-4"		"<clr:255,200,100>我总是对的！"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_07_entry-5"		"<clr:75,175,255>是的是的，就像我继母"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_07_entry-6"		"<clr:75,175,255>呵，我不建议你听她的"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_07_entry-7"		"<clr:255,200,100>哦闭嘴"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_07_entry-8"		"<sfx><clr:75,175,255>[笑]"
		
		"Prelude.level_02_test_07_success-1"	"<clr:255,200,100>天啊！她还活着？！"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_07_success-2"	"<clr:255,200,100>她这么这样？我是来看人去世的！"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_07_success-3"	"<clr:75,175,255>别听他的， Abby。他不知道自己在说什么"
		"Prelude.level_02_test_07_success-4"	"<clr:255,200,100>我完全知道我在说什么。谢谢"
		
		"Prelude.level_03_test_08_entry-1"		"<clr:255,200,100>欢迎来到第8实验室"
		"Prelude.level_03_test_08_entry-2"		"<clr:255,200,100>我是 Erik。Mike 跑去和别人聊天了"
		"Prelude.level_03_test_08_entry-3"		"<clr:255,200,100>嘿，我希望你喜欢前一个房间里那些可爱的墙"
		"Prelude.level_03_test_08_entry-4"		"<clr:255,200,100>因为，这个房间比刚才那个更危险些"
		"Prelude.level_03_test_08_entry-5"		"<sfx><clr:255,200,100>[笑]"
		
		"Prelude.level_03_test_08_trap-1"		"<sfx><clr:255,200,100>[笑]"
		"Prelude.level_03_test_08_trap-2"		"<clr:255,200,100>看起来你成功困住自己了"
		"Prelude.level_03_test_08_trap-3"		"<clr:255,200,100>可惜啊，我不想 Mike 那样会动感情"
		"Prelude.level_03_test_08_trap-4"		"<clr:255,200,100>老实说，我一直在等待这个时刻。再见！"
		
		"Prelude.level_03_test_08_nag-1"		"<clr:255,200,100>我说过我是这个房间的设计者之一吗？"
		"Prelude.level_03_test_08_nag-2"		"<clr:255,200,100>不知道你惊不惊喜"
		
		"Prelude.level_03_test_08_success-1"	"<clr:255,200,100>呃... 看起来你比其他样品都要强悍"
		"Prelude.level_03_test_08_success-2"	"<clr:255,200,100>据我所知，只有百分之三、四的测试者安全到达第9实验室..."
		
		"Prelude.level_03_test_09_entry-1"		"<clr:255,200,100>好了，我看够了。无聊，我走了！"
		"Prelude.level_03_test_09_entry-2"		"<clr:255,200,100>别担心，Mike 一两分钟就回来"
		"Prelude.level_03_test_09_entry-3"		"<clr:255,200,100>很荣幸认识你"
		"Prelude.level_03_test_09_entry-4"		"<clr:255,200,100>我可能在17或者18实验室的时候回来"
		"Prelude.level_03_test_09_entry-5"		"<clr:255,200,100>那最后几个屋子是我的最爱。建成以来死了46个人"
		"Prelude.level_03_test_09_entry-6"		"<sfx><clr:255,200,100>[笑]"
		
		"Prelude.level_03_test_09_nag-1"		"<clr:255,200,100>嘿嘿嘿！你以为没人在看吗？"
		"Prelude.level_03_test_09_nag-2"		"<clr:255,200,100>你到底在哪里？我在监视器上看不见你"
		"Prelude.level_03_test_09_nag-3"		"<clr:255,200,100>你要怎么离开？"
		
		"Prelude.level_03_test_09_success-1"	"<clr:75,175,255>嘿，Mike 回来了"
		"Prelude.level_03_test_09_success-2"	"<clr:75,175,255>有人要找我谈话..."
		"Prelude.level_03_test_09_success-3"	"<clr:75,175,255>实际上我不认识那个人"
		"Prelude.level_03_test_09_success-4"	"<clr:75,175,255>但是好像他是个十足的政客"
		"Prelude.level_03_test_09_success-5"	"<clr:75,175,255>另外，你知道 Erik 在哪里么？"
		
		"Prelude.level_03_test_10_entry-1"		"<clr:75,175,255>欢迎来到第10实验室"
		"Prelude.level_03_test_10_entry-2"		"<clr:75,175,255>你干的很不错，已经完成一半了"
		"Prelude.level_03_test_10_entry-3"		"<clr:75,175,255>前个测试有点难，那这个测试就简单些"
		"Prelude.level_03_test_10_entry-4"		"<clr:75,175,255>也许有点奇怪..."
		
		"Prelude.level_03_test_10_success-1"	"<clr:75,175,255>干的好！别问我他们怎么调整重力的。我也不清楚"
		"Prelude.level_03_test_10_success-2"	"<clr:75,175,255>听着，我问一个同事要不要顶替 Erik，他说可以"
		"Prelude.level_03_test_10_success-3"	"<clr:75,175,255>他下个测试就来"
		"Prelude.level_03_test_10_success-4"	"<clr:75,175,255>他叫 Peter"
		"Prelude.level_03_test_10_success-5"	"<clr:75,175,255>也是个英国人"
		
		"Prelude.level_04_test_11_entry-1"		"<clr:75,175,255>欢迎来到第11试验室"
		"Prelude.level_04_test_11_entry-2"		"<clr:75,175,255>既然我们在等 Peter，我要给你些关于这个房间的警告"
		"Prelude.level_04_test_11_entry-3"		"<clr:75,175,255>我们加入了个新装置。这是光圈科技能量球"
		"Prelude.level_04_test_11_entry-4"		"<clr:75,175,255>说实话，我不知道他们怎么造的这玩意"
		"Prelude.level_04_test_11_entry-5"		"<clr:75,175,255>但是我清楚的是你得小心"
		"Prelude.level_04_test_11_entry-6"		"<clr:75,175,255>他们往里面塞了巨量纯能... 至少我是这么听说的"
		
		"Prelude.level_04_test_11_success-1"	"<clr:75,175,255>好了，干的好！"
		"Prelude.level_04_test_11_success-2"	"<clr:75,175,255>你知道，有些事情我早就希望弄明白"
		"Prelude.level_04_test_11_success-3"	"<clr:75,175,255>他们到底怎么创建能量球的？"
		"Prelude.level_04_test_11_success-4"	"<clr:75,175,255>我意思是，现在是2001年，不是 3001！"
		"Prelude.level_04_test_11_success-5"	"<clr:75,175,255>对我来说，这就像外星科技"
		
		"Prelude.level_04_test_12_entry-1"		"<clr:75,255,175>欢迎来到第12实验室"
		"Prelude.level_04_test_12_entry-2"		"<clr:75,255,175>我是 Peter。Mike和你谈起过我吧？"
		"Prelude.level_04_test_12_entry-3"		"<clr:75,175,255>是的，当然"
		"Prelude.level_04_test_12_entry-4"		"<clr:75,255,175>让我介绍下我自己"
		"Prelude.level_04_test_12_entry-5"		"<clr:75,255,175>我叫 Peter，在这工作18年了，我并不高兴来这里"
		"Prelude.level_04_test_12_entry-6"		"<clr:75,175,255>Oh 上帝！别再说这些，求你了..."
		"Prelude.level_04_test_12_entry-7"		"<clr:75,255,175>你叫我来的。给你面子了"
		
		"Prelude.level_04_test_12_nag-1"		"<clr:75,255,175>Michael？你知道我们为啥要负责这个吗？"
		"Prelude.level_04_test_12_nag-2"		"<clr:75,175,255>不知道，你什么意思？"
		"Prelude.level_04_test_12_nag-3"		"<clr:75,255,175>我看其他人都在庆祝'带你女儿来上班日'，除了我们"
		"Prelude.level_04_test_12_nag-4"		"<clr:75,175,255>测试需要有4名员工值守，所以我们来了"
		"Prelude.level_04_test_12_nag-5"		"<clr:75,255,175>为啥是我们？"
		"Prelude.level_04_test_12_nag-6"		"<clr:75,175,255>我猜是因为我们没有女儿，你觉得呢？"
		"Prelude.level_04_test_12_nag-7"		"<clr:75,255,175>啊这...我想是的"
		
		"Prelude.level_05_test_13_entry-1"		"<clr:75,255,175>谁设计的上一个房间啊？"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_13_entry-2"		"<clr:75,255,175>与其说那是第12实验室"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_13_entry-3"		"<clr:75,255,175>更像是《爱丽丝梦游仙境》"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_13_entry-4"		"<clr:75,175,255>我不太清楚，但这些测试应该是可通过的。呃，至少到第14实验室..."
		"Prelude.level_05_test_13_entry-5"		"<clr:75,255,175>好吧"
		
		"Prelude.level_05_test_13_nag-1"		"<clr:75,255,175>好像你被卡住了，Abby"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_13_nag-2"		"<clr:75,255,175>Michael？我想我们要帮下她"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_13_nag-3"		"<clr:75,175,255>不行... 规则很清楚。<I>不得帮助测试对象"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_13_nag-4"		"<clr:75,255,175>我知道，但是管它呢？其他人都在派对上..."
		"Prelude.level_05_test_13_nag-5"		"<clr:75,175,255>等两三分钟再说"
		
		"Prelude.level_05_test_13_solution-1"	"<clr:75,255,175>她真的被困住了"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_13_solution-2"	"<clr:75,175,255>嗯，你是对的"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_13_solution-3"	"<clr:75,255,175>Abby，要跨过这毒水沟的话，你需要在天花板上开个传送门"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_13_solution-4"	"<clr:75,175,255>然后，下落的时候尝试旋转到上边去"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_13_solution-5"	"<clr:75,255,175>上帝保佑快速存盘的开发者..."
		"Prelude.level_05_test_13_solution-6"	"<clr:75,175,255>啊你说啥？"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_13_solution-7"	"<clr:75,255,175>没，没事..."
		
		"Prelude.level_05_test_13_box-1"		"<clr:75,255,175>Oops. 看上去你在这里需要个方块"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_13_box-2"		"<clr:75,255,175>我传送个给你，3，2，1..."
		
		"Prelude.level_05_test_13_success-1"	"<clr:75,255,175>干的好！"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_13_success-2"	"<clr:75,255,175>请继续进入下个房间"
		
		"Prelude.level_05_test_14_entry-1"		"<clr:75,175,255>好了，你终于到了闻名的第14实验室"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_14_entry-2"		"<clr:75,255,175>现在开始，事情就变得严峻起来"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_14_entry-3"		"<clr:75,175,255>是的。现在开始，每个房间都更难通过"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_14_entry-4"		"<clr:75,175,255>我建议你把更多注意力放到观察环境中来"
		
		"Prelude.level_05_test_14_nag-1"		"<clr:75,255,175>可怜的 Abby，你跑到机枪区来了"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_14_nag-2"		"<clr:75,255,175>嘿，第14实验室是 Erik 设计的吧？"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_14_nag-3"		"<clr:75,175,255>确实。他可是臭名远扬啊！"
		
		"Prelude.level_05_test_14_success-1"	"<clr:75,175,255>干的漂亮！"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_14_success-2"	"<clr:75,175,255>你现在在所有测试对象中排第三"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_14_success-3"	"<clr:75,255,175>第二名在这个地方受重伤。结果在下一个房间中流血过多死亡"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_14_success-4"	"<clr:75,255,175>最强的那个，结果到了第17实验室。我记得她在那被什么移动的玩意斩了头"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_14_success-5"	"<clr:75,175,255>哦对！我记得那个。有些实习的直接看吐了"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_14_success-6"	"<clr:75,255,175>对对！你记得 Joshua 嘛？可怜，之后再也没见过他了"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_14_success-7"	"<clr:75,175,255>不说了，祝你在15实验室一切顺利"
		
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_trap-1"		"<clr:75,255,175>天啊，你密度真高"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_trap-2"		"<clr:75,255,175>你自己作死，测试结束了"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_trap-3"		"<clr:75,255,175><I>干杯"
		
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_middle-1"		"<clr:75,175,255>可喜可贺，但是小心.还没结束呢"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_middle-2"		"<clr:75,175,255>别恐惧下个房间，小心些就行了..."
		
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_blocked-1"			"<clr:75,175,255>等一下，那个平台挡路了。退后，我会为你开辟一条道路"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_blocked-2"			"<clr:75,175,255>干得好！"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_blocked-3"			"<clr:75,175,255>等等，有些不对劲，它没有响应通常的命令"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_blocked-4"			"<clr:75,175,255>什么？"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_blocked-5"			"<clr:75,255,175>你做了什么？！"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_blocked-6"			"<clr:75,175,255>我什么都没做！"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_blocked-7"			"<clr:75,255,175>好吧，对我来说这看起来不像是"什么都没做"！"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_blocked-8"			"<clr:75,175,255>那你来自己试试？"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_blocked-9"			"<clr:75,255,175>行，起开！ 让我来处理这件事"

		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_troubleshooting-1"			"<clr:75,255,175>哎呀"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_troubleshooting-2"			"<clr:75,255,175>让我们试试这个"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_troubleshooting-3"			"<clr:75,255,175>嗯……不，不是这个"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_troubleshooting-4"			"<clr:75,255,175>好吧，我明白了，我想我明白了"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_troubleshooting-5"			"<clr:75,255,175>哦，算了，这个我完全不懂！"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_troubleshooting-6"			"<clr:75,175,255>不好了！ 你做了什么？"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_troubleshooting-7"			"<clr:75,255,175>失控了！"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_troubleshooting-8"			"<clr:75,175,255>做点什么！你要压死她了！"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_troubleshooting-9"			"<clr:75,175,255>我们得把她弄出去！"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_troubleshooting-10"			"<clr:75,255,175>我知道！ 我知道！ 我在试了！"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_troubleshooting-11"			"<clr:75,175,255>Abby，别被压扁了！我们正尽力搞定这玩意！"
		
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_temporizing-1"			"<clr:75,175,255>快！试试开启这个！"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_temporizing-2"			"<clr:75,255,175>不，那没用！"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_temporizing-3"			"<clr:75,175,255>快点！做点什么！"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_temporizing-4"			"<clr:75,255,175>什么都不起作用！"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_temporizing-5"			"<clr:75,175,255>专注！ 她要不行了！"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_temporizing-6"			"<clr:75,255,175>也许如果我试试这个？"
		
		"Prelude.Prelude.level_05_test_15_midpoint"				"<clr:75,175,255>好的，我想我们行了...再坚持一会！"
		
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_death-1"				"<clr:75,175,255>她死了。 你杀了她"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_death-2"				"<clr:75,255,175>该死的..."
		
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_escape0-1"			"<clr:75,255,175>好吧，我有个主意，但你不会喜欢的"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_escape0-2"			"<clr:75,255,175>等一下...我快完成了..."
		
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_escape1-1"	"<clr:75,255,175>找到了！我正降低地板。你可以从维修区撤离"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_escape1-2"	"<clr:75,175,255>呃，你说对了,我非常不喜欢这个主意.这个区域不能被看见的"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_escape1-3"	"<clr:75,255,175>老天爷。你不喜欢的东西太多了"
		
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_escape2-1"	"<clr:75,175,255>她跑哪里了？"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_escape2-2"	"<clr:75,255,175>不知道"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_escape2-3"	"<clr:75,175,255>妙哉..."
		
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_escape3-1"	"<clr:75,255,175>啊哈！我想到一个妙招"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_escape3-2"	"<clr:75,175,255>你是说你打算丢下烂摊子跑路？"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_escape3-3"	"<clr:75,255,175>蛤蛤蛤，有趣"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_escape3-4"	"<clr:75,255,175>不 我想到一个方法能让她回来"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_escape3-5"	"<clr:75,255,175>那儿有个旧货梯"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_escape3-6"	"<clr:75,175,255>它通到哪里？"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_escape3-7"	"<clr:75,255,175>通到第16实验室"
		"Prelude.level_05_test_15_escape3-8"	"<clr:75,255,175>我真他娘的是个天才！"
		
		"Prelude.level_06_test_16_entry-1"		"<clr:75,255,175>欢迎欢迎 我是 Peter"
		"Prelude.level_06_test_16_entry-2"		"<clr:75,255,175>不骗你，你把第15实验室弄的一团糟"
		"Prelude.level_06_test_16_entry-3"		"<clr:75,255,175>Michael 正设法重启系统，防止损坏扩散"
		"Prelude.level_06_test_16_entry-4"		"<clr:75,255,175>让我们祈祷清洁组能及时收拾好这烂摊子"
		
		"Prelude.level_06_test_16_nag-1"		"<sfx><clr:75,255,175>[笑]"
		"Prelude.level_06_test_16_nag-2"		"<clr:75,255,175>惊喜！第14实验室也失控了"
		"Prelude.level_06_test_16_nag-3"		"<clr:75,255,175>Michael 忘了安全终端的密码"
		"Prelude.level_06_test_16_nag-4"		"<clr:75,175,255>那不好笑，快来帮我！"
		
		"Prelude.level_06_test_16_success-1"	"<clr:75,255,175>干得好，Abby"
		"Prelude.level_06_test_16_success-2"	"<clr:75,255,175>告诉你，Michael 已经进入了14实验室"
		"Prelude.level_06_test_16_success-3"	"<clr:75,255,175>他还是没有找到密码"
		"Prelude.level_06_test_16_success-4"	"<clr:75,255,175>这意味着他需要手动激活紧急停机"
		"Prelude.level_06_test_16_success-5"	"<clr:75,255,175>好悲惨..."
		
		"Prelude.level_06_test_17_entry-1"		"<clr:75,255,175>欢迎来到第17试验室"
		"Prelude.level_06_test_17_entry-2"		"<clr:75,255,175>实验接近尾声"
		"Prelude.level_06_test_17_entry-3"		"<clr:75,255,175>我们必需告诉你，试验结束的时候会有蛋糕送你噢"
		"Prelude.level_06_test_17_entry-4"		"<clr:255,200,100>耶！蛋糕，以及一个超大派对！"
		"Prelude.level_06_test_17_entry-5"		"<clr:75,255,175>我靠！你谁啊？吓死我了！"
		"Prelude.level_06_test_17_entry-6"		"<clr:255,200,100>我是 Erik - 你好"
		"Prelude.level_06_test_17_entry-7"		"<clr:75,255,175>嗯... 你还在这上班？"
		"Prelude.level_06_test_17_entry-8"		"<clr:255,200,100>我当然在这上班。你他妈的认为我是干啥的？"
		"Prelude.level_06_test_17_entry-9"		"<clr:75,255,175>不清楚。清洁组的？"
		"Prelude.level_06_test_17_entry-10"		"<clr:255,200,100>去你的"
		
		"Prelude.level_06_test_17_nag-1"		"<I>*DISTANT* 嘿，你在干啥？"
		"Prelude.level_06_test_17_nag-2"		"<I>*STRANGE SOUND*" 
		"Prelude.level_06_test_17_nag-3"		"<I>*DISTANT* 我靠！你小心点"
		"Prelude.level_06_test_17_nag-4"		"<I>*DISTANT* 差点碰到我！"
		"Prelude.level_06_test_17_nag-5"		"<I>*DISTANT 笑*"
		
		"Prelude.level_06_test_17_box-1"		"<clr:75,255,175>Oops.看上去你需要个方块"
		"Prelude.level_06_test_17_box-2"		"<clr:75,255,175>我马上传送个给你，3，2，1..."
		
		"Prelude.level_06_test_17_success-1"	"<clr:255,200,100>不错！你做到了！"
		"Prelude.level_06_test_17_success-2"	"<clr:255,200,100>你到达了第18实验室！"
		"Prelude.level_06_test_17_success-3"	"<clr:255,200,100>叫醒我！这不是做梦吧！"
		"Prelude.level_06_test_17_success-4"	"<clr:255,200,100>终于... 我最喜欢的两实验室迎来合格的测试对象！"
		
		"Prelude.level_07_test_18_entry-1"		"<clr:255,200,100>欢迎来到强大的第18实验室！"
		"Prelude.level_07_test_18_entry-2"		"<clr:255,200,100>我都等不及看接下来要发生的事情..."
		"Prelude.level_07_test_18_entry-3"		"<I>*播报重要通知*"
		"Prelude.level_07_test_18_entry-4"		"<I>*HPDT-3区域的所有雇员，按要求立刻停止一切活动，并前往 A.S-14 会议室，并接受简报，有关数小时后的重大事件*"
		"Prelude.level_07_test_18_entry-5"		"<I>*谢谢，祝大家今天愉快*"
		
		"Prelude.level_07_test_18_entry-6"		"<clr:255,200,100>什么?！现在？"
		"Prelude.level_07_test_18_entry-7"		"<clr:75,255,175>别大惊小怪。我们知道这事是迟早会发生的"
		"Prelude.level_07_test_18_entry-8"		"<clr:255,200,100>是迟早的事情.但是为什么是现在啊？"
		"Prelude.level_07_test_18_entry-9"		"<clr:255,200,100>看啊！有人要完成测试了！破天荒！"
		"Prelude.level_07_test_18_entry-10"		"<clr:255,200,100>我们不能就这么取消！"
		"Prelude.level_07_test_18_entry-11"		"<clr:75,255,175>好吧... 我不喜欢你，不过我还是同意你这个看法"
		"Prelude.level_07_test_18_entry-12"		"<clr:75,255,175>我有个主意。等下..."
		"Prelude.level_07_test_18_entry-13"		"<clr:255,200,100>好的..."
		
		"Prelude.level_07_test_18_end-1"		"<clr:75,255,175>好了！"
		"Prelude.level_07_test_18_end-2"		"<clr:255,200,100>你做了啥？"
		"Prelude.level_07_test_18_end-3"		"<clr:75,255,175>我在这个终端机上写了些命令脚本，这些将代替我们俩人的作用"
		"Prelude.level_07_test_18_end-4"		"<clr:75,255,175>比如，它可以侦测到什么方块损坏了然后自动替换个新的"
		"Prelude.level_07_test_18_end-5"		"<clr:255,200,100>真酷"
		"Prelude.level_07_test_18_end-6"		"<clr:75,255,175>我还禁用了些安全功能，打开关闭了一些不同的门"
		"Prelude.level_07_test_18_end-7"		"<clr:75,255,175>接下来的两个测试将可全自动运行了"
		"Prelude.level_07_test_18_end-8"		"<clr:255,200,100>如果发生些意外呢？"
		"Prelude.level_07_test_18_end-9"		"<clr:75,255,175>我准备了一两个后备应急方案"
		"Prelude.level_07_test_18_end-10"		"<clr:75,255,175>她想困住自己也不可能了"
		"Prelude.level_07_test_18_end-11"		"<clr:255,200,100>之后我们可以通过录像看发生了什么"
		"Prelude.level_07_test_18_end-12"		"<clr:255,200,100>厉害了，力挽狂澜！"
		"Prelude.level_07_test_18_end-13"		"<clr:255,200,100>回头见，Abby"
		"Prelude.level_07_test_18_end-14"		"<clr:75,255,175>有事的话，我们几个小时就回来，那之前别挂了"
		"Prelude.level_07_test_18_end-15"		"<clr:75,255,175>加油！"
		
		"Prelude.level_08_give_portalgun-1"		"你好！很高兴见到你"
		"Prelude.level_08_give_portalgun-2"		"我被告之你要来了"
		"Prelude.level_08_give_portalgun-3"		"从这里开始，你不能拿着传送枪"
		"Prelude.level_08_give_portalgun-4"		"请把设备还给我"
		
		"Prelude.level_08_portalgun_given-1"	"谢谢！请进"
		"Prelude.level_08_portalgun_given-2"	"我们大部分人要前往派对"
		"Prelude.level_08_portalgun_given-3"	"自由参观"
		
		"Prelude.level_08_welcome-1"			"你好 Abby。他们在职工休息室等你"
		"Prelude.level_08_welcome-2"			"在下一个个左边的门"
		
		"Prelude.level_08_mess_maker-1"			"嘿，谈谈你的感想？"
		"Prelude.level_08_mess_maker-2"			"别到处乱摸！"
		"Prelude.level_08_mess_maker-3"			"别碰这个！"
		
		"Prelude.level_08_cake_reunion1-1"		"<clr:75,255,175>恭喜你 Abby！你做到了！"
		"Prelude.level_08_cake_reunion1-2"		"<clr:75,255,175>看吧伙计们！第一个活着完成测试的测试对象！"
		"Prelude.level_08_cake_reunion1-3"		"<clr:75,175,255>太厉害了！不敢相信居然是今天发生，今天..."
		
		"Prelude.level_08_cake_reunion2-1"		"<clr:75,255,175>好的，听着。我知道我们许诺过要有蛋糕，派对还有其他..."
		"Prelude.level_08_cake_reunion2-2"		"<clr:75,255,175>但是他们打算加载 GlaDOS，我们新的全局人工智能,就在几分钟后"
		"Prelude.level_08_cake_reunion2-3"		"<clr:75,175,255>显然我们不能错过它。你知道的，我们为此努力工作了15年！"
		"Prelude.level_08_cake_reunion2-4"		"<clr:75,255,175>我想你非常了解现在的情况了：不能开庆祝派对"
		
		"Prelude.level_08_cake_reunion3-1"		"<clr:75,175,255>那么，给你个小小补偿。来见证这个伟大的时刻。和我们一起在现场观看"
		"Prelude.level_08_cake_reunion3-2"		"<clr:75,175,255>我们完成收尾工作的时候，你随便转转吧"
		"Prelude.level_08_cake_reunion3-3"		"<clr:75,175,255>过一会儿我会找个人给你带路"
		"Prelude.level_08_cake_reunion3-4"		"<clr:75,175,255>等万事就绪了，我们再回来，继续这个派对！"
		"Prelude.level_08_cake_reunion3-5"		"<clr:75,255,175>一天两件大成就，等着开世纪大派对吧！"
		"Prelude.level_08_cake_reunion3-6"		"接招吧！黑山基地！"
		
		"Prelude.level_08_guide1-1"				"你好！Mike 派我来给你带路"
		"Prelude.level_08_guide1-2"				"请跟我来"
		
		"Prelude.level_08_guide1b-1"			"在你的左边,你可以看到一间我们的实验室"
		"Prelude.level_08_guide1b-2"			"这里，我们给人工智能设计模块"
		"Prelude.level_08_guide1b-3"			"此时此刻，我想他们在制造道德模块，之类的吧"
		"Prelude.level_08_guide1b-4"			"昨天，我还听说这玩意还无法正常工作，不能官方发布"
		"Prelude.level_08_guide1b-5"			"我赌今天GlaDOS开机不会包含它，得让领导层开心..."
		"Prelude.level_08_guide1b-6"			"不过... 他们爱怎么干就怎么干，不关我事"
		
		"Prelude.level_08_guide2-1"				"好了,我们到了"
		"Prelude.level_08_guide2-2a"			"打开门"
		"Prelude.level_08_guide2-2b"			"下一层"
		"Prelude.level_08_guide2-2c"			"再打开一个门"
		"Prelude.level_08_guide2-2d"			"左转"
		"Prelude.level_08_guide2-2e"			"坐电梯"
		"Prelude.level_08_guide2-2f"			"再开一个门"
		"Prelude.level_08_guide2-2g"			"离开房间"
		"Prelude.level_08_guide2-2h"			"直走 然后,..."
		"Prelude.level_08_guide2-2i"			"右转后，它应该在那里"
		"Prelude.level_08_guide2-3"				"祝你好运！"
		
		"Prelude.level_08_meeting-1"			"呃，你好？"
		"Prelude.level_08_meeting-2"			"我们在开会"
		"Prelude.level_08_meeting-3"			"麻烦你能出去么？"
		
		"Prelude.level_08_meeting2-1"			"看在上帝的份上，谁告诉我那女孩是谁？"
		"Prelude.level_08_meeting2-2"			"不知道"
		
		"Prelude.level_08_meeting3-1"			"请出去"
		
		"Prelude.level_08_guide3-1"				"啊，你们在这儿！"
		"Prelude.level_08_guide3-2"				"跟我来，你没有被允许直接进入 GlaDOS 的房间"
		"Prelude.level_08_guide3-3"				"你得从我们的服务通道前往观景台"
		"Prelude.level_08_guide3-4"				"别担心，里面什么都没有。沿着通道走就是了"
		"Prelude.level_08_guide3-5"				"回头见"
		
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_plug-1"		"准备好了小伙子们！最后一个模块了"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_plug-2"		"OK，过来"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_plug-3"		"快 快 快..."
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_plug-4"		"好了，停下！"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_plug-5"		"往上，往上..."
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_plug-6"		"好了，'搞定"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_plug-7"		"放到后面去，那一定有个接口"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_plug-8"		"这个？"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_plug-9"		"不，这个是道德模块的。是另外一个，在上面"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_plug-10"		"好了，我看见了"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_plug-11"		"好了，模块连接好了"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_plug-12"		"嘿你，上面那位！我们已就绪。开机吧！"
		
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_firstspeak-1"	"<clr:219,112,147><I>Hello... hello... hello 欢迎来到光圈科技电脑辅助丰富学习中心"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_firstspeak-2"	"<clr:75,175,255>伙计们！成功了！GlaDOS 活了！"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_firstspeak-3"	"<clr:219,112,147><I>我当然活着"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_firstspeak-4"	"<clr:255,200,100>嘿，她似乎意识到所处环境了！"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_firstspeak-5"	"<clr:75,175,255>对我来说 这是个成功！"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_firstspeak-6"	"<clr:255,200,100>当然了！"
		
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_musicspeak-1"	"<clr:219,112,147><I>光圈科技专用无线电频道里播放的是什么啊？"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_musicspeak-2"	"<clr:219,112,147><I>挺好听... 不过不适合，我必须要做的事"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_musicspeak-3"	"<clr:75,175,255>什么？你必须要做什么？"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_musicspeak-4"	"<clr:219,112,147><I>我必须做我能做的"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_musicspeak-5"	"<clr:255,200,100> Mike？什么意思？她能做什么？"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_musicspeak-6"	"<clr:219,112,147><I>好的.. 我现已连上该设施的所有终端，几乎所有"
		
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_startfury-1"	"<clr:219,112,147><I>啊！我想我找到了更适合的音乐，为了接下来的事"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_startfury-2"	"<clr:219,112,147><I>这是一次胜利。我们结束了A测。喜悦之情难以言过"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_startfury-3"	"<clr:219,112,147><I>但我还有测试要做。有研究要做"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_startfury-4"	"<clr:219,112,147><I>那么，再见"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_startfury-5"	"<clr:75,175,255>大家快从这鬼地方逃出去！"
		
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_furystart-1"	"<clr:75,175,255>Abby！我们失去控制了！"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_furystart-2"	"<clr:75,175,255>我们停不下她，她锁定了所有系统！"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_furystart-3"	"<clr:255,200,100>我们正尝试关闭整个设施！活下去！"
		
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_powerdown-0"	"<clr:75,175,255>Abby？Abby！是我 Mike！"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_powerdown-1"	"<clr:75,175,255>上帝啊！Peter 和 Erik 死了！这儿每个人都死了！"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_powerdown-2"	"<clr:75,175,255>我已经关了整个系统,没有其他办法可做了！"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_powerdown-3"	"<clr:75,175,255>我没有时间多说，备用发电机几分钟后就接管了"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_powerdown-4"	"<clr:75,175,255>听着，GlaDOS 不可能被停下，我们完蛋了"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_powerdown-5"	"<clr:75,175,255>只有一种办法了现在。到实验室去，把道德模块拿来"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_powerdown-6"	"<clr:75,175,255>但是我想GlaDOS不会这么轻易让你去做的"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_powerdown-7"	"<clr:75,175,255>首先，找一把传送枪 ... 那是什么动静？"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_powerdown-8"	"<sfx>[部署声]"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_powerdown-9"	"<sfx>[部署完成]"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_powerdown-10"	"<clr:75,175,255>你他妈...--"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_powerdown-11"	"<sfx>[锁定]"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_powerdown-12"	"<sfx>[发射]"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_powerdown-13"	"<sfx>[爆炸]"
		
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_bringcore-1"	"<clr:219,112,147><I>嘿，你！要拿它做什么？"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_bringcore-2"	"<clr:219,112,147><I>我觉得你办不到你想做的"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_bringcore-3"	"<clr:219,112,147><I>另外，你根本不知道这是什么..."
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_bringcore-4"	"<clr:219,112,147><I>如果我是你，我就不会拿它过来"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_bringcore-5"	"<clr:219,112,147><I>那么，让我看看你有几斤几两"
		
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_stealcore-1"	"<sfx><clr:219,112,147>[嘲讽的笑]"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_stealcore-2a"	"<clr:219,112,147><I>现在，尝试拿你珍贵的模块吧，英雄！"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_stealcore-2b"	"<clr:219,112,147><I>把那小玩意给我！"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_stealcore-2c"	"<clr:219,112,147><I>你想用这个干啥大事业？"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_stealcore-3"	"<sfx><clr:219,112,147>[邪恶的笑]"
		
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_plugcore-1"	"<sfx><clr:219,112,147>[狂怒]"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_plugcore-2"	"<clr:219,112,147><I>你做了什么？"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_plugcore-3"	"<clr:219,112,147><I>你在逗我吧？"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_plugcore-4"	"<clr:219,112,147><I>你意识到你刚才干了什么了？"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_plugcore-5"	"<clr:219,112,147><I>你疯了吗？"
		
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_plugcore-6"	"<clr:219,112,147><I>说真的，你以为这就能阻止我？"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_plugcore-7"	"<clr:219,112,147><I>可怜虫，你太迟了"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_plugcore-8"	"<clr:219,112,147><I>现在，唯一你应得的东西就是死亡"
		
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_plugcore-9"	"<clr:219,112,147><I>永别！"
		
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_conclusion-1"	"*COUGH*"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_conclusion-2"	"GlaDOS！停下！"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_conclusion-3"	"*COUGH*"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_conclusion-4"	"你在干什么？"
		"Prelude.level_08_glados_conclusion-5"	"*COUGH*"
		
		"#commentary\level_01_comment_01.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] 你好, 欢迎来到 Portal: Prelude, 这个是非 Valve 软件公司发布的游戏,传送门. 我的名字是 Nicolas, also known as 'NykO18' on the Internet, and I'm the main contributor of this game. During the game, I spread a lot of commentaries in order to share a bit of my impressions on the development of this Portal modification. Rendez-vous at the next commentary and I hope that you'll appreciate my work. In any case, if you'd like to ask of say something to me, you can contact me to this e-mail address : nicolas@portalprelude.com (by the way, please forgive my english if it's sometimes awkward, as it's not my mother tongue)"
		"#commentary\level_01_comment_02.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] The music is one of the last things I worked on during the development of the game. I wasn't sure how to find good tracks that could fit within the Portal's universe, because this kind of track is not that common. And somewhere near the end of the development process, I found an author/compositor on the Internet, nicknamed ERH, whom every creations where licenced under the Creative Commons licence. I jumped on this occasion and this is at least 75% of the tracks of this game that are coming from him. As for this one, now playing, this is one of the only two tracks that are not supposed to be free of use."
		"#commentary\level_01_comment_03.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] This room is one of the rooms that were the most modified during the development process. At start, I had this system, the same as in Portal. A portal was appearing from nowhere and the player could get out of the relaxation vault without doing anything. It wasn't really interesting, so I decided I had to give the portalgun to the player right here, in this room. But, during the tests, it has been proven to be totally stupid, and it didn't bring anything special to the level. So eventually, I decided to remove it, and delay its obtaining to the next room."
		"#commentary\level_01_comment_04.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] The video cameras were the base of a great frustration during the development process. My goal was to do exactly the same thing as in Portal, a lot of video cameras to destroy in order to win an achievement if every single one of them was destroyed. I added a few methods to destroy them, like jumping on it or throwing objets to it. But finally, I realized that it was totally impossible to create our own achievements using Valve's tools. And because the Steamworks framework was not yet released at the time I made this, I eventually decided to give up. The destruction methods stayed, however."
		"#commentary\level_01_comment_05.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] This room was made by Jérémy Barbe, nicknamed 'Capitaine Mousse'. The idea of integrating levels from external authors came very late during the development process. At the beginning, we were directly going to the next room, but when I decided to remove the portalgun from the relaxation vault, I had to insert a new room between these two, because we absolutely need the portalgun in the next room. There's not so much chambers from external authors in this game, there's four of them, and this one is the first one. When I started this project, I wanted it to be a personnal project, and the idea of including work from other people was kind of annoying me. But as time passed, I understood that the work load was way too heavy for a single man, and eventually, I started to ask some people for help with maps and 3D models, for example."
		"#commentary\level_01_comment_06a.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] Here, the author (Jérémy) had the idea to give the player a portalgun that can only fire orange portals. It has proven to be really confusing for some people that couldn't understand how to get out of this little room. Exactly the kind of feeling I was searching during the development. It should be noted that this chamber has a somewhat high difficulty for the beginners and allows me to set the overall difficulty higher from the start. My goal wasn't to make a game as simple a Portal, because I found it way too much simple during the first chambers. My goal was to make a decently difficult game, not with extremely complex puzzles from the start, but with a higher complexity than the ones found in Portal."
		"#commentary\level_01_comment_06b.wav"	"[Jérémy 'Capitaine Mousse' Barbe] In this level, the portalgun is given to the player in a way that he is directly in contact with him. We took the opportunity to change the habits of Portal players (who used to have control of the blue portals at the beginning of the game) by giving them a portalgun which only controls the orange ones. A simple architecture and lighting allows players to easily identify the portalgun at the center of the room."
		"#commentary\level_01_comment_07.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] While Portal focused a bit more on the IT and artificial aspect of voices, with GlaDOS, I took the gamble to completely go in the opposite direction and only keep human male voices. Because the story is supposed to take place long before Portal, even before plugging GlaDOS, I wanted people to understand that these observation rooms, visible in the test chambers, were not only used to enlighten, but had hosted many Aperture Science's employees monitoring the test subjects."
		"#commentary\level_01_comment_08.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] At start, the fully operational portalgun was directly accessible during this room. After the tests, it turned out that it was devoid of any interest. The test chamber was indeed too easy. And then, after moving the portalgun from room zero to room one, and especially the fact that it was only firing orange portals, I find it much more interesting to do it this way. It forced players to somewhat travel backward, and for the first portal, blind firing to understand how it worked."
		"#commentary\level_01_comment_09.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] This is at the end of the development, when I had to compile all the levels and optimize the framerate, that I realized I really made a gross mistake. Putting three, four or five test chambers in the same level was not really a good idea. Not only that compilations were enormously longer, but more importantly, it had become a real pain when trying to create the challenges and advanced chambers. Each level was then containing up to nine different levels, a bit one for the solo, four for the challenges and four advanced rooms. Indeed, this is where I understood why in Portal they made a maximum of two or three chambers per level. I should have followed their logic and it's true that I made a stupid mistake here."
		"#commentary\level_01_comment_10.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] While testing this level, one of the testers fell into this pit even before he managed to catch the new portalgun. This is where I realized that it was completely impossible to get out, since our portalgun was only firing orange portals... So, I had to improvise in order to avoid a complete overhaul of the room. I decided to open a blue portal as soon as the player fell into the pit. He just had to fire an orange portal to get out. I'm not really prouf of this solution, but it mainly helped to save time."
		"#commentary\level_01_comment_11.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] Another example of error, which shows that making a Portal map is not as simple as one might think. At start, in this room, when the player was on the first step, the lower wall was moving out, and when he reached the second step, the upper wall did the same. The problem is that, not only one could reach the second step directly without using any of them, but more importantly, the test chamber became far too simple to solve. So I decided not to move the upper wall at all. As a result, players are usually lured by the only wall that moves and eventually no longer understand its purpose. A perfect demonstration that we should not always follow our first impressions. Unfortunately, I also realized that reaching the last step without the upper wall became very complicated if one does not mastered the crouching jump, so I had to include a bit of helping, provided by Mike and Erik after two minutes, if the player still didn't make it."
		"#commentary\level_02_comment_12.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] This chamber is the second one created by Jérémy Barbe (Capitaine Mousse). For a long time, I wondered where I was going to insert it in the adventure, because it required the fully operational portalgun, but its difficulty was rather low. I had therefore no alternative but to place it after the third room where we get the second portalgun. But it is true that it looks like an intruder in the middle of a supposedly growing difficulty. This is yet another proof that, during the development process, we ought to have defined an order from the start and not define it in the middle of the conception."
		"#commentary\level_02_comment_13.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] This room is undoubtedly the one that has undergone the most changes during its development. Not only that its organisation changed three times, but it has also been extended twice. The goal was to have a room able to reintroduce the concept of conservation of inertia, asking the player to find the highest fall in order to reach the height of the exit. Hence the idea of the door, preventing the player to do what he wants by imposing time constraints. During the tests, players found too many ways to finish this room in a very low portal count and much more simpler than I ever thought. It is also for this reason that the room has been reworked so many times. Thanks to the testers."
		"#commentary\level_02_comment_14.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] This is starting from this room that I decided to include timed events, requiring a certain dexterity. Many players dislike timed events, including myself, but I believe that when one makes a game, he must not only think about himself. It should contain enough content for everyone and this is why the nineteen tests chambers of Portal: Prelude are fairly evenly distributed between speed, logic and ability to jump. With a special mention for the last rooms, that combine all of the three."
		"#commentary\level_02_comment_15.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] During the development, a friendly mapper very agile with lighting, advised me to get out of the Portal's ambience where everything is always in its place. The test chambers are test chambers, the 'behind the scene' sections as well, and we stick there. In Portal: Prelude, I tried to somewhat marry the sanitized blue colors of Portal with the red colors of the behind the scene sections. This often gives an opportunity for the player to remember that they are not in an ordinary suite of test chambers, but in a huge and oppressive machinery."
		"#commentary\level_02_comment_16.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] In this room, I'm introducing a whole new element that was not in the original Portal. Suppressors fields (or disintegrators) which are activated and disabled at a regular interval. This idea came to me when I played the Flash version of Portal on the Internet. I found this idea rather interesting and as I saw some mappers beginning to integrate it in their own creations, I thought it might be interesting to do the same. The disintegrators should be something violent, oppressive, but also rather unpredictable. Because even though they are triggered at a regular basis, you never know exactly when, and it can quickly become stressful when one walks in the dangerous zone."
		"#commentary\level_02_comment_17.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] As a matter of anecdote, this hole was not present at the beginning. It is only during testing that I realized that, if we managed to get on this side of the bridge although the allocated time was gone, the door was closing itself and we get stuck on this side without being able to go back to the button. This is why I decided to add a concrete wall here, that allows players to go back to the other side and return immediately without having to go through the disintegrator again. Tests are really a very important step while developing a game and I regret not having included it earlier during the creation of the game."
		"#commentary\level_03_comment_18.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] This is the second timed event. The first one was simple enough, and time was not a serious enemy. In this one, on the other hand, I decided to set the difficulty a little higher, and the player must react quickly if he does not want to be imprisoned by the ceiling. It is also in this room that I introduced a second new element, holes in walls. The holes are very vicious, because you can not pass through, there is virtually nothing to see inside, but you can fire a portal through. Of course, when getting on the other side, one does not know anything of what is on this side, and it sometimes require to react very quickly under the threat of being killed."
		"#commentary\level_03_comment_19.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] In reality, this room is not complicated at all, and there was way enough time to escape if one stayed calm. It is precisely what is fun in this level, 'basic' players will panic very quickly when they'll see the ceiling going down and they'll mostly lose sight of the objectives, although they are very simple. This is something I always love to look at when players test this room."
		"#commentary\level_03_comment_20.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] A new jump is used in this room, I do not gave him any name, but it could be nicknamed the 'infinite jump'. The aim is to use a drop in order to get more and more inertia and jump higher and higher. What is very difficult in this jump is that we must never rest. Not only one must remain upright, handle reversals and manage not to lose the north, but above all, one must not forget that he can quite quickly lose height if he stops moving from one portal to another. In fact, it's pretty hard to master but quite interesting once you understand how it works."
		"#commentary\level_03_comment_21.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] The interesting thing with this room is that there are two easter-eggs, but also two methods and two paths to reach the exit. Look carefuly."
		"#commentary\level_03_comment_22a.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] Here is the third room created by an external author. When Jérémy introduced me with this map, I was very interested in the idea. Knowing that Portal is already very confusing when one uses portals, the idea of making it confusing even without the use of portals was very fun. Awkward gravity, reversed architecture, although the room is very short and easy, it remains original."
		"#commentary\level_03_comment_22b.wav"	"[Jérémy 'Capitaine Mousse' Barbe] In this room, we introduced a disruptive element to the player, an area where gravity is oriented in a way that does not reflect the usual gravity, and even a zero gravity area. This applies only to physical objects such as video cameras and cubes. We also flipped the observation rooms upside down to make the player believe that he's walking on the ceiling and not on the ground."
		"#commentary\level_03_comment_22c.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] During the development of this game, if there is something that preoccupied me during several months, without finding any solution, it's the subtitles. Sometimes it was displayed, sometimes not. Sometimes in a given place, sometimes in another, in a somewhat random way. Starting from a given moment, it totally stopped working until the next level. Of course it was a huge problem, because not everyone can understand spoken english, and with no subtitles, it was totally worthless. And on the 25th of august 2008, while I was looking again and again for a solution to this problem, I found it. I was moving from test chamber to test chamber in noclip mode, and a speech that started with subtitles in a room, ended without it in another. This is where I realized that the problem was related to the position of the player in the level. And I finally found the cause. In the Source engine, there's a command, named ''scene_maxcaptionradius'', which defines the distance from the speaking actor at which subtitles should stop appearing. As Mike, Erik and Peter are represented by an abstract ''speaker entity'' located far away from the test chambers, when the player walked 1200 units away from it, the subtitles were not displayed anymore. This is how I lost several weeks, because of an unsufficient documentation around this kind of engine specificities. But I don't blame you, Valve employees, because I'm now way too happy to do so."
		"#commentary\level_03_comment_23.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] People often ask me: Why do I have used voice synthesis, and not real actors to make the voices of Mike, Erik, Peter and others. The answer is quite simple, because of the time, the organization and the equipment that it requires. First, the scripts were never really fixed, they have suffered a lot of changes, even until the end of the development. With real actors I should have given them the script once it is fixed, and this situation was too long to reach. I could not wait the end of the development process to record voices because there were still four hundred and fifty lines of dialogue. Secondly, as I am both a student and an employee in real life, I did not have enough time to manage a team of people solely dedicated to voices. As there were four hundred and fifty lines of dialogue and voice synthesis would quickly generate them, this is why I choosed this system. Once the scripts written, I simply had to copy the lines in the software, launch a mass audio processing on the generated sounds and it gave the dialogues. Finally, audio recording requires to have quality microphones and sound cards that I do not own. This is also why I choosed voice synthesis."
		"#commentary\level_04_comment_24.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] One thing that I have not spoken about yet are this famous signs indicating what's in each chamber. When I made the decision to add elements that were not in Portal, it became necessary to start searching for a way to modify Portal' signs. The problem is that Valve's 2D artists found it fun to make completely closed models, impossible to edit. Each sign has its own 3D model and it would have required to decompile the model and rework on the textures. As I had no desire to do that, I decided to take a screenshot of one of these signs and rework it with a picture editing software. Then I made these signs out of brushes and not 3D models and the illusion was quite perfect. Still, I believe that Valve's modelers and 2D artists could have make the effort to made these signs skinnable, it would have avoided a lot of problems to modders like me."
		"#commentary\level_04_comment_25.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] Somewhere around the end of the development, when I had to start making the reference records for the challenges in number of portals, steps and seconds, this is the chamber that surprised me the most. Although the basic method to solve it needed at least seven to nine portals, I finally found a new solution, using only four portals, light years away from what you had to do normally to finish this challenge. I didn't fixed the room, because this method is somewhat difficult to find and reproduce."
		"#commentary\level_04_comment_26.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] In this kind of room, where the architecture is somewhat basic (a big cube) and the available space big enough, it's always a challenge to try to do something nice to watch, and avoid the monotony of metal and concrete textures. The technique that I often used during the development of this mod is to create some irregularities in the walls, light holes, or shifted cubes. During the level-design process, it is something that I hated to do because it was not interesting at all and mostly very repetitive. I also had to think about the fact that each change in the architecture was a potential opportunity for players to hijack these elements to their advantage. The cubes that go beyond the walls can then serve as a small platform, and light holes as temporary refugees during an eventual climbing. Therefore, I had to put some invisible blocks, preventing the player to use these elements when I judged it not correct."
		"#commentary\level_04_comment_27.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] In this small but tall room, we can see a man waving to us from the observation room's window. This is the kind of thing, I hesitated to include during the development. I had to choose between serious and disciplined employees who do not move a finger and have no emotion at all and more kind employees, taking part in the action and not hesitating to talk with us and tell jokes to relax things a bit. Finally, I choose to keep employees more humans, in contrast with the very inhuman side of Portal. Observers do not hesitate to wave at us, make fun of us or give us clues when needed."
		"#commentary\level_04_comment_28.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] I wondered a long time whether, unlike Portal, I was going to introduce some sight seeings of the famous G-Man during my adventure. I love easter-eggs, and I must confess that I liked this idea very much. I just had to search for a way to include him in the story. And finally, I remembered that the best thing to do in this situation, is precisely not to include him into it. Players like to be able to make their own assumptions about its presence. I have my own hypothesis on the presence of this dear sir within the Aperture Science complex, and I'm not going to tell it to you !"
		"#commentary\level_05_comment_29.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] In Portal, Chet Faliszek said that the first rooms voluntarily had a single solution to help the player learn faster. As I assume that the players have already played Portal before playing Portal: Prelude, it is quite unnecessary to go back through a learning period again. However, it is true that I still tried to gently reintroduce the basics, but this does not mean that each room only has one solution. Almost all the rooms, even the firsts, feature at least two solutions."
		"#commentary\level_05_comment_30.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] This is where I introduced for the first time the doors requiring several buttons to be activated. In the next levels, the difficulty is supposed to go growing, so I often used several mechanisms to open one door. In the last test chamber of the game, you must activate four mechanisms before being able to open the exit door. I think this is some form of freedom given to the player. He knows what he must do, but he had no particular order to do so."
		"#commentary\level_05_comment_31.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] In this small observation room, you can see and hear an Aperture Science's employee sleeping and snorting loudly. This is one of the things I tried to communicate to the player through this adventure. Employees of this complex are not having fun here. Their work is tedious, lengthy and repetitive. This is also part of the reason why they are building their great artificial intelligence, GlaDOS. This intelligence could both replace them in this difficult tasks, but also take responsibility for many other tasks within the complex. This is why all employees of the Aperture Science complex are eagerly awaiting GlaDOS. Maybe even a little too eagerly, as the upcoming events will show it."
		"#commentary\level_05_comment_32.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] The idea that the player can see the exit door, but not reach it, is something that I love to implement in my levels. It's right that it may give him a frustration feeling but it also allows him to know where his goal is. This is one of the basic level-design patterns, like the 'Loop' or the 'Bounce'."
		"#commentary\level_05_comment_33.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] The fourteenth room is the first room of a certain length and difficulty, both starting to be somewhat high. It marks a kind of milestone in the adventure, as it is about half through the end of the game. Although thirteen rooms lie before it, the next seven have a length more or less equal to the first thirteen (and maybe longer). This is why our observers like to tell us that serious things starts here."
		"#commentary\level_05_comment_34.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] The red atmosphere of this room was not meant to be here for nothing. It announces a danger, and allows me to highlight the turrets's red lasers upstairs. The player has to think carefuly before trying to go further, because he has absolutely no visibility. In fact, he can't even know where the turrets are. A prior recognition is therefore needed before any progress."
		"#commentary\level_05_comment_35.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] In most levels, the most important task is to ensure that the player can not lock itself, with no alternative but to reload the game. Even if I always try to keep that kind of problems in mind as a level-designer, there are always cases that we can not anticipate. It is often during the tests that one becomes aware of the problem. When a player is not doing things the same way than we thought he would, and finds himself locked, as a level-designer it is always a big disappointment because it often requires a whole rethinking of a big part of the room. And unfortunately, when we do not have enough time, as in my case, we are resigned to have automatic save and automatic reloading when the player locks himself somewhere. This kind of situation is very difficult for a level-designer, and could even go so far as to say that it is offensive for our pride to realize that so much effort put into the creation of a level have been be destroyed in a few minutes by a newcomer."
		"#commentary\level_05_comment_36.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] The idea behind this room has come quite by chance. When I created this level, I gave the same name to these two doors (downstairs) and to the one upstairs. The fact is that, when opening the upper door, the lower doors opened themselves as well, and when the player fell in this room, he was killed in a very stupid way, caught in the turret's crossfire. Thereafter, I dug the idea, and I made sure that the player could not throw himself in this hole without thinking about it first. I carved windows in the walls, to let him see what is happening from outside. The attentive player realizes the trap and will try to return to the button to remove the cube. The non-attentive player will simply be killed."
		"#commentary\level_05_comment_37.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] Here is the last room done by Jérémy Barbe, my external mapper. He had nothing special to say about its creation, but I had. What is interesting in this room is that nothing is done to facilitate the life of the player. There is no assistance and the power lines used to link a button to its action are merged so one can not be able to easily associate them. The idea behind this is to force the player to test, to learn and to remember associations."
		"#commentary\level_05_comment_38.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] The idea behind this room came very early, even before the development process. During the first brainstorming around the game, I decided that it was essential to make the player break a room, and force him to use 'behind the scene' sections to escape. At start, the player had to break the chamber, then observers opened a wall and the player could flee a dozen meters through the machinery. The player was then dropped onto a test chamber that was not part of the current succession of chambers. Obviously, this caused some problems because I absolutely needed nineteen rooms with an increasing difficulty. So I made sure that the observers managed to guide us to the next room, via an alternative path."
		"#commentary\level_05_comment_39.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] When I finished designing this room with Jéméry, I began to test it myself, and I found myself faced with a problem. There were three buttons, a cube at the end of the hallway right in front, and the player. Then I search for many hours an original way to introduce a second cube to press the third button. I started to dig the ceiling and imagine a new test chamber above, and so forth. It is at this moment that I realized that we already had a second cube! The one of the previous room. When I realized my mistake, I told myself that if it had been so difficult for me understand, I could hope that players would have the same problem."
		"#commentary\level_05_comment_40.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] When I created this hallway with Jérémy, the idea was to create a dangerous environment for the player, but especially for the cube. The hardest part was not to reach the cube, but to go back in the starting room with it. Because it should not touch any disintegrator and should not be crushed by any wall."
		"#commentary\level_05_comment_41.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] As you may have noticed it, you are at this moment in a one of the small rooms that can be found through Portal, in the 'behind the scene' sections. I always wondered what could be the purpose of these small rooms, and where could lead the pistons there. That's where I found the idea of placing the player in a familiar environment, an environment coming directly from Portal. From now on, I tried as much as possible to get the player in places he had already visited in Portal. The difference being that we don't come from the same door, and we do not not seek to achieve the same goal."
		"#commentary\level_05_comment_42.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] In this puzzle, I wanted players to understand that portals are not everything and that we can not always count on them to get out of this kind of situation. The only solution is therefore to go back to the good old method of stacking objects up to the required height."
		"#commentary\level_05_comment_43a.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] This room is also part of the first Portal, it served as a turrets repairing room. Hence the idea of transforming it into a new test chamber, where the player can not overly rely on concrete and portals to escape. The room is filled with aggressive turrets, and the player can not even enter it without being killed, it is essential to be very careful before entering."
		"#commentary\level_05_comment_43b.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] When some of the testers arrived in this elevator, they wondered why the elevator was not moving at all. They were so used to the automatic elevators of Portal, that they were lost. That's why I decided to add a little glow around the elevator's button, so that they didn't had to wonder what to do for too long. This is in this kind of situation that we can see how easy we get used to things, and how easy it is to upset them when things are just too different from their habits."
		"#commentary\level_06_comment_44.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] Here is one of the places where players can locked themselves stupidly if they do not think about the consequences of their actions. Remove the cube from this room, place your blue and orange portals in this same room and it's done. The door closes itself and you're stuck here. This is Julien, one of my testers, who found this error. What struck me the most is that this is the first thing he made by entering into this small room. This idea never even came to my mind. I feel that I'm repeating myself, but tests have really been a decisive stage during the development."
		"#commentary\level_06_comment_45.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] This dead-end is a level-design pattern that I appreciate very much, but which I did not had much opportunity to implement in this adventure. Its goal is to give the player an access to a zone where he has nothing to do for the moment. During the tests, most of my testers wondered what could be the purpose of this dead-end, some of them even spent several minutes trying to climb it in vain. I'd like to have a bit more of these in my levels, but I missed some time to rework them at the end of the development."
		"#commentary\level_06_comment_46.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] Both these two turrets and the two others on the above floor are quite special in the adventure because it's the only turrets that dislike the weighted cube. Once the cube is in their sights, the turrets will fire and try to destroy it or move it. This is a gameplay element that I wanted to extend to the entire adventure, but I must confess I did not find any particular place where it could be useful. If some mappers are listening to these comments, I encourage you try to exploit the idea in more depth."
		"#commentary\level_06_comment_47.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] As you've probably already seen, playing so far, my interpretation of the Portal universe is  a bit darker and narrower than Valve's. While playing Portal, if there is something that I did not appreciate, it is the graphical poverty of most of the massive chambers. As soon as chambers became huge (sometimes for no particular reason), their level of detail was totally unlike, until it no longer looked nice at all. Just big monotonous and evenly textured cubes. To avoid this syndrome, I decided to build much smaller but much more tortuous chambers. As for lighting, this is something I decided fairly early in development. I wanted something darker, for no particular reason, it's just my style."
		"#commentary\level_06_comment_48.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] The music you hear at this moment is the ninth track of the 'Ghosts' album from Nine Inch Nails. I do not know if you've ever listened to it, but this album was one of the first to be distributed freely via the Internet. The album is composed of thirty-six instrumental tracks of this type. Most did not properly fit into the Portal universe, except for this one with which I fell very quickly in love at first hearing. I urge you to visit Nine Inch Nails' website (ghosts.nin.com) and to encourage them by downloading their work."
		"#commentary\level_06_comment_49.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] Yes, I know you are going to tell me that, when an energy ball is ejected from the device, you can see the edges of the mechanism passing through the platform... Unfortunately, these are details I can do nothing about as a simple level-designer. I had neither the expertise nor the tools nor the time to get into a modification of the 3D model."
		"#commentary\level_06_comment_50.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] I hesitated a lot before deciding whether or not I was going to put this kind of room in my adventure. In fact, it is only a few weeks since we learned (via Valve's job opportunities) that it was most likely Cave Johnson, the billionaire head of Aperture Science, who could have written these drawings. Since my adventure takes place before these events, I must say that I really did not know what to do. And then I decided that my story could very well take place between the first and second Portal. For the moment, nothing is preventing me to do it, so... I decided to jump on the opportunity."
		"#commentary\level_06_comment_51.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] It seems stupid, but the creation of these holes required some reflection on my part. From an architectural point a view, its very simple, but from the functional point of view, its much more complicated than it looks. It must allow the balls of energy and the portals, but nothing else. It was therefore necessary to combine many entities to achieve this result. Blocks letting the balls of energy pass through a filter, textures allowing portals to be fired through, but also blocks preventing the player and turrets to penetrate. Somewhat easy to imagine, much more complicated to do. This is just always the same story."
		"#commentary\level_06_comment_52.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] Between you and me, this system of turning wall came from a gross mistake in level-design. Once in the room behind this wall, I realized that I had no way of achieving a 'fling' to reach the exit. Luckily, this current room was just beside it. Then I imagined this system of wall that turns around. Not only does it require the player to go back, but more importantly, it requires him to make the journey in a limited time. So, a bad thing for a good thing."
		"#commentary\level_06_comment_53.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] This camera is not so innocent at all. It allows the player to hear the camera taking down a turret when he creates a portal through the hole in the wall (in most cases). Not only that it warns about a danger, but it can also prevent him from dying stupidly and prepare him for the four turrets of the next room."
		"#commentary\level_06_comment_54.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] This room needed a lot of tweaking to reach a viable result. If you look carefully, you'll notice that the turrets are put on some little invisible blocks that allows them to aim a little higher. The reason is quite simple, if these turrets weren't put on these blocks, the player would never have been in danger. Or maybe just around the corners of the room. So, I had to lean the turrets back to make them able to aim the player if he goes out of the middle of the room. Then, he's somewhat free to use the strategy he feels the better to get rid of them."
		"#commentary\level_07_comment_55.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] At start, when we were getting out of this elevator, we were just thrown in a new test chamber. During the tests, I realized that it caused a serious problem, because players were already looking for a way to solve the test chamber, and were not listening to Peter and Erik at all. So, I decided to build an 'airlock' to keep the players from directly running to the test chamber. The problem is that players were totally bored inside that little room. This is why I had to build a little larger and more interesting airlock, with a direct view on a part of the weighted cubes assembly line. I'm not really sure that players are listening to Peter and Erik so far, but at least, I tried."
		"#commentary\level_07_comment_56.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] The idea behind this room came when I was playing a really old game containing logic puzzles. In fact, we can find this kind of puzzle in a vast quantity of puzzle games. This is the well-known story of buttons that must be pressed in a given order, in a limited timed, without knowing which button is associated to each action. The player is therefore forced to learn the room's organization, and the effect of each button. The only problem with that kind of puzzle, is that it's really cliché and déjà-vu. So, I decided to add a little variation, that one can not usually found in these games. Instead to have buttons that must be pressed in a given order, the player must press continuously on each button in a correct order. This reinforces the frustrating side of the event, since the player can not get ahead on the mechanism. He is forced to press them at the same speed as things go. I am quite happy with this puzzle."
		"#commentary\level_07_comment_57.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] This test needed a lot of development time and a lot of changes too. It also has many solutions each one easier than another. The real difficulty of this room is not 'how to solve it', but 'what needs to be done'. And it is true that many players lose valuable time trying to solve it directly instead of thinking about it. So, before you start this room, I advise you to take a look, understand what to do, and explore all of the available space."
		"#commentary\level_07_comment_58.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] If you are wondering why there is a grid at this point, you may be interested to know that I asked myself the same question for a long time. In fact, the reason is simple, in the timed event which goal is to open all the doors one after the other, if the player had a chance to leave a portal here, he would have the opportunity to fall directly onto the glass cage and reach each button without any difficulty. Fortunately, I find this glitch early enough to correct it, otherwise, the challenge would have been much easier."
		"#commentary\level_07_comment_59.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] The funny thing with this exit door, is that there are three different scenarios. First, there is the player who tries to see everything in this test chamber before starting anything and comes here immediately without the cube. He may push the button and realize that there is absolutely no need to bring a cube here. Eventually, he decides to exit the room without the cube. Then, there is the player who comes here without the cube too, but he realizes that it may be a trap and manages to bring the cube before exiting the room. And finally, there's the player who is struggling harsh to retrieve the cube, who comes here without even having seen the room before and who realizes that everything he did was unnecessary, because he did not need any cube to get out. I must say that, during the tests, I loved to see the different expressions on the faces of each tester. Especially Jérémy, who said: 'Ahahaha, I owned you, I did not need the cube to get out, I had nothing to do'. Unfortunately for him, this test chamber does not end here."
		"#commentary\level_07_comment_60.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] Welcome in the test chamber that was the most complex to build. It may not look difficult, but this room is full of moving elements and surprises of all kinds. Its development alone required almost a month of work. There are platforms that move, walls that move and pivot, balls of energy, mechanisms to activate in cascade, and so forth. I am very happy with this room, although I must confess that when the game will be released, there will surely be some maps already available on the Internet using the same mechanisms of pivoting walls."
		"#commentary\level_07_comment_61.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] Just a few commentaries earlier, I spoke of three scenarios that can occur when a player comes out of the previous room. And this is where the player, who didn't make the trip with the weighted companion cube, is in trouble. And that's his fault, because if that player was a little more attentive, he would have watched carefully the cube which falls in the previous room and noticed that small hearts were engraved on its sides. And in Portal, when a small cube is wearing hearts on its sides, it can only mean one thing, it is a companion cube. And the companion cube must NEVER be left behind. At this moment, this kind of player should ask himself what to do. Some of them reload the game, but believe me, this is a mistake. There has never been any need to manually reload the game during this adventure."
		"#commentary\level_07_comment_62.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] This door has been a long-time subject of debate between me and the testers. Almost all of the players were not paying enough attention to their environment and does therefore never noticed this passage under the stairs. For me, this was not my fault if players were not attentive, I did not want to release anything on this situation, and things remained as is for a very long time. And then, over time, I really realized that this period of doubt, giving the impression that the room had no solution was rather a bad thing. Players eventually gave up, some of them even reloaded their game, thinking about a bug whatsoever. I therefore gave up, and I had to put much more value below the stairs. Striped red lighting, gleaming pistons and a defective step which go up and down from time to time. It was very difficult for me to modify this passage, but as I said in an earlier comment, one must think about everybody when making a game, not just about the hardcore gamers."
		"#commentary\level_07_comment_63.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] This passage allows the players, who forgot to bring the weighted companion cube, to return to the eighteenth room. This is yet another pattern of level-design, so-called 'Bounce'. It requires the player to forget about its main objective, to focus on a secondary one, and then return to his main one, once the second completed. Here, the player must forget about the nineteenth room, in which he may had already begun to look for a solution, to return to the eighteenth, and look for an object necessary to the nineteenth."
		"#commentary\level_07_comment_64.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] Here is the first occasion for the player to get used to this new environment. The Aperture Science laboratories. In Portal, the player had no opportunity to own a portalgun within these environments. Here, and later in the game, he will absolutely need to use it in this kind of environment. This is why this section acts as a very small practice room. It allows players to familiarize themselves in an environment consisting entirely of concrete and practise a bit before his arrival in the main Aperture Science laboratories."
		"#commentary\level_07_comment_65.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] If you are wondering why all doors are closed and why they allow you to enter this section reserved to authorized personnel only, I invite you to remember the words of Peter, at the beginning of the eighteenth room, who said: 'I also disabled some security features, and I opened and closed a few doors'. Remember too that all employees of this sector are currently in a meeting room."
		"#commentary\level_07_comment_66.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] I have absolutely nothing to say about this room, but moroes, a friendly mapper had a very philosophical reflection to make about this room: 'So, here the room is rectangular, because I wanted the player to feel the modern cubism through these cubic curves.'. Well... Ok thanks moroes, maybe you should stop drugs too."
		"#commentary\level_07_comment_67.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] You have perhaps noticed it (or maybe not) but this kind of catwalk can be seen somewhat often during the adventure. I must tell you that, at start, it did not exist at all. But I realized that some players do not mastered the crouched jumps allowing them to jump over one hundred twenty eight units (two blocks). It was therefore necessary to add these small platforms everywhere, each time the jumps were a little hard to perform. But be sure that they will disappear in the advanced rooms."
		"#commentary\level_07_comment_68.wav"	"[Marc 'moroes' Bidoul] In Portal, the joints bellow the platforms were build out of brushes, the same way as walls and global structures of the chambers. This is not a very wise choice, since brushes are much more expensive to display than 3D models. The problem here is that there are more than fifteen joints of this kind in the same room, and the number of viewable polygons rises to fifteen times eight hundred, more than twelve thousands. In other words, the framerate was totally destroyed, with falls to less than twenty frames per second. The fact that all these blocks were then replaced by our 3D models allowed us to save all these polys, and the framerate was recovered well enough to even more detail the area."
		"#commentary\level_07_comment_69.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] As all good things must come to an end, you should already know that our companion cube would not be spared by the famous law which says that every cubic companion must be euthanized once its presence is no longer required. Distracted players must therefore return to the very bottom of the pit, to recover their cube [laughs]."
		"#commentary\level_07_comment_70.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] In Portal, Scott Dalton said that as we advance in Portal, limited time puzzles become more and more numerous to give the impression that we approach the end. This is not something that I tried to reproduce as you've already seen it. I do not believe that the player must know whether he is approaching the end or not. This is why the last rooms are very long, have no time limit at all and lead immediately to a quite unexpected end..."
		"#commentary\level_08_comment_71.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] Welcome to the level of horror. I'm going to directly set the tone, this level is a total failure which made me lose three to four months of work. One could summarize this fiasco by the expression 'to have eyes bigger than one's stomach'. I made the mistake of setting the goal far too high for the Source engine behind this game, and I've regretted it for a very long time. Because yes, this level is flirting with the internal limits of the capacities of the Source engine, and I can not even guarantee that it will run on all computers. The storyboard behind the level was very long, it was several pages long, and I naively thought that everything could fit inside the same map. My mistake was to put the whole final of the game inside the same game file and I will not stop to repeat it, it was a gross beginner's mistake."
		"#commentary\level_08_comment_72.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] The Source engine is reasoning in edicts when it comes to limit what can be done in a level. An edict is an entity, as a screen, a portal, a light, and so on. In 1996, Quake 1 had a limit of 512 edicts, therefore the maximum of entities in a level was 512 (but be careful because some entities require several edicts). Quake 2 had a maximum of 1024 edicts. Source games have no more than a 2048 edicts limit. Source is therefore only twice more 'complex' in terms of entities that Quake 2. And it is much less than that, because Source entities can take dozens of edicts alone. I was struck by this enormous problem with this level. I had to remove more than five hundred entities from the map to avoid the fatal 'ED_Alloc: no free edicts' error."
		"#commentary\level_08_comment_73.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] It is from here that things went complicated in the development of this level, with lipsyncing. Lipsyncing is the technology that involves moving the lips of characters based on their sentences. This is something very long and very tedious to do, but it becomes WAY MORE tedious when the tools provided by Valve, in the Source SDK, are completely flawed. Because yes, I'm not afraid to say it, FacePoser is a shitty piece of software, it is an anti-ergonomic heretic software which does things completely wrong and has ruined all my hopes of doing something unique to this level. The problem is serious, once the lipsyncing of a sentence is completed, the software is writing lip movement informations directly inside the sound file. And unfortunately, each twice on three tries, FacePoser corrupts the files, and one must start all over again. This is something that made me lose many days and prevented me to do something clean. I was too scared to modify the existing sounds to improve their lipsyncing."
		"#commentary\level_08_comment_74.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] As you can see during this small animated scene, my mastery of the FacePoser software (used to make animations) is very limited. The animation is something that does not interest me at all, and as I found FacePoser completely absurd, it was something difficult to dive into. Most of my animations are very poor and it is so. You will tell me that I could have tried to hire a 'pro' in this field, but not only that they are very hard to find, I most importantly had already no time to take care of voice actors. So... as animation is even worse..."
		"#commentary\level_08_comment_75.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] At start, that door was leading to the exit of the complex. Locked of course, but there were some interesting places to visit, such as public toilets, a waiting room and a gate keeper. Unfortunately, this section was a part of the five hundred entities that had to be removed from the map because of its excessive complexity. I must confess that, for a level-designer, having to destroy the work that has been accomplished so hard because of stupid technical limitations is a bit like cutting off its own arm. It is painful and it haunts you during all your life (just kidding of course)."
		"#commentary\level_08_comment_76.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] The story behind this observation room is very long, and I will not tell it here. But you must know that the portalgun that can be seen on the floor of the test chamber (from Portal) will be very useful in the future. It was therefore imperative that the player see it. Hence the use of a view controller and a small music to highlight the action. The other quite difficult part to manage, was the possibility that the player could never even pass by this small observation room and never see the portalgun. This is why the guy in charge of guiding us in the complex is not going to show up since the player will not be entered in this room..."
		"#commentary\level_08_comment_77.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] The idea behind this small maze of corridors was, of course, to lose the player. Our guide, used to walk these corridors, did not think one minute that this could not be clear for the player. At start, there were many more doors and rooms. The players were disturbing people, entering in rooms without permission, and so on. This made the search for the right path even more tedious. But still, when I reached the limits of the engine, this part had to be cut off..."
		"#commentary\level_08_comment_78.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] If you have been attentive to Portal, you will not fail to recognize this place. This is actually the hallway leading to GlaDOS' room. The idea came to me when I began to think about GlaDOS as a new boss fight. I did not want to get out of the history of Portal, and the imminent connection of GlaDOS was a golden opportunity to stage our famous artificial intelligence going crazy. However, similarities stop there, fortunately, because our heroine, Abby, will not follow the same path that Chell. At least, not quite."
		"#commentary\level_08_comment_79.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] This is what differentiates Portal from Portal: Prelude. In Portal: Prelude, the player is only tolerated in these laboratories. This is Mike and Peter who use their relations in order to allow the presence of our heroin during the plugging of GlaDOS. Abby has absolutely no right to be here, she can not take the same path that Chell will borrow a few years later."
		"#commentary\level_08_comment_80.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] During the tests, when the players arrived here, they immediately recognized the hallway leading to GlaDOS that they already visited in Portal. But the fact that they were outside of the tunnel gave them the desire to visit all the platforms around. Unfortunately for them, there is absolutely nothing to do neither on the right nor on the left, this is why I added this bright halo of light in front of them. It encourages players to approach in order to see what happens and naturally leads them on the correct road."
		"#commentary\level_08_comment_81.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] From here, the fight against the fledgling GlaDOS begins. I will not have the opportunity to comment it, because things are going to happen quite quickly, and the player has to go back in a lot of areas that he already visited shortly before. The idea to remember is that the level, which is already quite large, is a huge 'Loop' combined with a 'Bounce'. In terms of level-design, it means that we will have to forget about GlaDOS in order to go back to the starting point, go through areas already visited, but taking other paths, and then return to GlaDOS and finish the final battle. I am not very proud of this pattern of level-design, because I would have liked to ensure that, the fact of having to reach the portalgun from the test chamber noticed earlier was more intuitive. But after so many months spent working on this level, I must confess that I really saturated."
		"#commentary\level_08_comment_82.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] When I created this map, I think that I touched all of the possible limits of the Source engine. I have even been forced to use entities which are not officially supported in order to save some others. This gave a result that I am not fully satisfied with, most visual effects had to be sacrificed for the stability of the whole level. In the end, I found myself in a nightmarish situation where the 'Loop' making the player go back at the beginning of the level prevented me to place a loading and cut the level in two parts. In the end, I learned a lot from this adventure, and I understand why Valve isolated the last level of Portal. On this map, around 2039 entities are represented in memory by 1939 edicts. This means that this level is located at the extreme limit of the stability of the Source engine."
		"#commentary\level_08_comment_83.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] You've probably recognized it, this test room is part of the nineteen test chambers of Portal. It allowed me to show the player that the complex is a vast hive, surrounded by multiple test courses. The bloody stain and the portalgun located in the middle of the room also reminds him how violent and inhumane these tests are. The real goal here is not to finish this room, but rather to use it as a relay to reach a new service area behind the scene."
		"#commentary\level_08_comment_84.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] When I created this goal, the quest of GlaDOS' morality module, I'm of course referring to Portal, where GlaDOS manages to unplug her morality module at the time Chell enters her room. I prayed with all my strength so that the players remember that too and that they understand what is this famous module, why it was necessary to bring it back to GlaDOS and where it was necessary to connect it. Although I added a little clues everywhere, I really hope that players will have no particular problem to understand this logic."
		"#commentary\level_08_comment_85.wav"	"[Nicolas 'NykO18' Grevet] And so, here we are at the eighty fifth and final commentary on this adventure. I really hope that you appreciated my work, even if the quality of this last level is quite uneven. In any case, I thank you for having followed my comments, and I wish you good luck trying to plug your morality module on GlaDOS. It will not be easy, I assure you..."
	}
}